<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-09-03T17:03:59+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Thought Leadership Blog</title><subtitle>A personal blog sharing insights on artificial intelligence, strategic thinking and product management.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Product Management Essentials</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/product%20management/2025/09/03/product-management/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Product Management Essentials" /><published>2025-09-03T12:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-09-03T12:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/product%20management/2025/09/03/product-management</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/product%20management/2025/09/03/product-management/"><![CDATA[<p>Product management sits at the crossroads of customer needs, technical feasibility and business viability. Here are some timeless principles I’ve learned:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Start with the problem.</strong> Always ground your work in a real user need. Avoid falling in love with a solution before validating that the problem exists and is worth solving.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Prioritise ruthlessly.</strong> There will never be enough time or resources to build everything. Use frameworks like RICE (Reach, Impact, Confidence, Effort) or MoSCoW (Must, Should, Could, Won’t) to guide trade‑offs.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Ship iteratively.</strong> Embrace a mindset of continuous delivery. Small, frequent releases allow you to gather feedback early and often, reducing risk and enabling course corrections.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Communicate clearly.</strong> Effective product managers are great storytellers and translators. Keep stakeholders aligned by sharing progress, challenges and context regularly.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Over the coming months I’ll share case studies and practical tools that have helped me in my own product journey. Stay tuned!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Product Management" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fundamental principles for building products users love.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Strategy Frameworks for Uncertain Times</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/strategy/2025/09/03/strategy-frameworks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Strategy Frameworks for Uncertain Times" /><published>2025-09-03T11:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-09-03T11:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/strategy/2025/09/03/strategy-frameworks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/strategy/2025/09/03/strategy-frameworks/"><![CDATA[<p>Great strategy isn’t just about setting a destination – it’s about choosing how you’ll get there when the path is uncertain. Here are a few frameworks I frequently use:</p>

<h3 id="ooda-loop">OODA Loop</h3>

<p>Originally developed for fighter pilots, the Observe–Orient–Decide–Act loop encourages continuous situational awareness and rapid iteration. In business contexts it reminds us to ground decisions in real‑time feedback rather than rigid plans.</p>

<h3 id="wardley-maps">Wardley Maps</h3>

<p>Wardley Mapping visualises the evolution of components in a value chain against market maturity. This helps teams understand where to invest in innovation versus commoditise. Drawing your own map can reveal surprising insights about your competitive landscape.</p>

<h3 id="three-horizons-model">Three Horizons Model</h3>

<p>This framework separates initiatives into three horizons: core activities (H1), growth opportunities (H2) and future bets (H3). Balancing investment across these horizons allows organisations to sustain the present while building for the future.</p>

<p>These tools are complementary and no single framework fits every situation. The key is to experiment and adapt them to your context, and to revisit your strategy regularly as conditions change.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Strategy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to think about planning and resource allocation when the future is unclear.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">AI Trends to Watch in 2025</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ai/2025/09/03/ai-trends/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AI Trends to Watch in 2025" /><published>2025-09-03T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-09-03T10:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ai/2025/09/03/ai-trends</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ai/2025/09/03/ai-trends/"><![CDATA[<p>Artificial intelligence continues to evolve at a rapid pace. Here are a few themes I’m watching closely as we head into 2025:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Responsible AI becomes mainstream.</strong> Organisations are moving beyond AI ethics pledges and beginning to bake principles like fairness, accountability and transparency into their development workflows. Expect more open‑source toolkits and regulatory guidance to support these efforts.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Edge computing meets machine learning.</strong> With advances in model compression and specialised hardware, we’re seeing more powerful models running on devices at the edge. This reduces latency and preserves privacy by keeping data local.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Foundation models and fine‑tuning.</strong> Large foundation models (like language and vision transformers) are enabling rapid prototyping through fine‑tuning. Businesses that can quickly adapt these models for domain‑specific tasks will gain a competitive edge.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>The field is broad, but focusing on these trends will help you stay ahead of the curve. In future posts I’ll dive deeper into each of these areas and share practical tips for product teams.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="AI" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Key developments shaping the artificial intelligence landscape.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to the Thought Leadership Blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2025/09/03/introduction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to the Thought Leadership Blog" /><published>2025-09-03T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2025-09-03T09:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2025/09/03/introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2025/09/03/introduction/"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to my new blog! Over the coming weeks and months I’ll be exploring topics that sit at the intersection of technology, business strategy and product development.</p>

<p>I’ve started this platform because I believe there’s tremendous value in sharing knowledge openly. Whether you’re a seasoned practitioner or just starting out in one of these fields, I hope the ideas and resources here will help you think differently about your work.</p>

<p>In particular, you can expect posts about:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Artificial intelligence</strong> – practical insights into how AI is being applied today and what’s on the horizon.</li>
  <li><strong>Strategy</strong> – frameworks and mental models to help make smarter decisions in uncertain environments.</li>
  <li><strong>Product management</strong> – hands‑on techniques for building and iterating products that truly solve user problems.</li>
</ul>

<p>Everything published here will strive to be accessible to readers using assistive technologies. If you spot something that could be improved from an accessibility perspective, please don’t hesitate to reach out.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="General" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An introduction to this blog and what you can expect.]]></summary></entry></feed>